okay Chris Kevin Lee sent us a message
好的Chris Kevin Lee给我们发了一条消息
this week first of all says hi Robbie
本周 首先说喜 罗比
this tweet is actually related to
这条推文实际上与之相关
episode 490 so this is last week Chris
第490集， 所以这是上周克里斯
was watching the show says a friend's
正在看节目说朋友的
PlayStation 3 had problems and I ran
PlayStation 3有问题， 我跑了
Dede rescue this is something you
Dede救援这 是 你的 事
learned on the show last week episode
在上周的节目中了解到这一节目
490 her drive has got 27 errors and he
490她的驱动器有27个错误，他
posted this screenshot so thank you very
贴了这个截图，非常感谢你
much for that that helps us we're gonna
对我们来说有用的东西很重要
refer right back to that in just a
再回过头来看一下
moment's time here carrying on with your
片刻的时间在这里 继续你的
your message there on Twitter you said I
你在 Twitter上的消息， 你说 我
recommended her to replace the hard
建议她更换硬盘
drive do you think that maybe that's the
开车你觉得那可能 是那个
best option Sasha what do you think I
最佳选择 Sasha你觉得我怎么样？
would say yes I would say just go for it
会说是的， 我会说只是为了 它
just place the drive replace the drive
只需放置驱动器更换驱动器
go for it go for it okay one of those
去吧， 好吧其中一个
Kingston's absolutely get one of those
金士顿绝对是其中之一
Kingston the kingston solid state drives
金士顿金士顿固态硬盘
what can you say i would investigate
你能说我会调查什么
just a little bit further okay because
再多一点 好吧 因为
here's the thing Chris we need to
这就是克里斯我们 需要的东西
understand that errors do not
明白错误不会
necessarily mean failure okay hard
必然意味着失败好吧
drives over the course of their lifespan
在他们的生命过程中开车
sometimes they will encounter bad
有时他们会遇到坏事
sectors and things like that
部门和类似的事情
let's refer back to your comment where
让我们回顾一下 您的评论
you said that your scan using DD Rescue
你说你的扫描使用DD Rescue
found 27 errors so let's think about the
发现了27个错误让我们考虑一下
process of running DD Rescue and what
运行DD Rescue的过程和什么
that means please refer back if you're
这意味着如果你是的话 请 回头
not familiar with what I'm talking about
不熟悉 我在说什么
I know Chris says but if you're watching
我知道克里斯 说， 但如果你在看
this and you haven't seen it go back to
这个，你还没有看到它回去
episode 490 of category 5 technology TV
第5类 技术电视 第490集
it's going to teach you all about this
它会教你 所有这些
but DD Rescue is it's trying to do a
但DD Rescue正在尝试做一个
data recovery copy of your hard drive to
你的硬盘数据恢复副本
an image file or another hard drive so
图像文件或另一个硬盘驱动器，从而
if you get 27 errors in the process it's
如果你在这个过程中得到27个错误
going it basically means 27 times I was
它基本上意味着我是27次
trying to copy this block of data which
试图复制这个数据块
by default is very small about 500
默认情况下，非常小约500
kilobytes so unless you specify a larger
千字节， 所以除非 你指定一个更大的
size and this is why I didn't show you
大小， 这就是我没有告诉 你的原因
to make as larger size which would be
制作更大的尺寸
faster but because we're working with
更快，但因为我们正在合作
drives that we assume are probably prob
我们假设的驱动器可能是概率
problematic we're gonna work with
有问题我们正在与 要去工作
smaller block sizes so
更小的块大小
as its copying it says 27 times I had
因为它的 复制它说了27次
trouble copying that so there's a couple
麻烦复制，所以有几个
things here first of all you you know
在这里你首先要知道的事情
that there's some data loss okay we're
这有一些数据丢失还好我们
gonna look at how much in just a second
要看看有多少， 一秒钟
as it's copying okay DD rescue can try
因为它复制 好DD救援可以尝试
again
再次
but what DD Rescue does is it says oh
但DD Rescue做的是它说 哦
okay I've found a problem here this
好吧， 我在 这里发现了一个问题
could mean that the drive is going to
可能意味着驱动器将要去
fail so let's move on let's let's really
失败所以让我们继续吧让我们真的
quickly skip over this and let's move on
快速跳过这个，让我们继续前进
to the next sectors and let's keep going
到下一个部门，让我们继续前进
because it wants to get the most amount
因为它想获得最多的金额
of data off of your hard drive as it
你的硬盘驱动器 的数据
possibly can before that drive fails
可能在该驱动器失败之前
because we're making the assumption that
因为我们正在做出这样 的假设
we might have a bad drive so then you
我们可能会有一个糟糕的驱动器，所以你
can run the scan again using your log
可以使用您的 日志 再次运行扫描
file or you can set it up to loop back
文件或您可以将其设置为 循环 回来
and this is through the command line
这是通过命令行
options so do a dash dash help to find
选项，所以做破折号帮助找到
out about those or read the man pages
关于那些或阅读手册页
and what it will do then is it will
它 会做 什么呢 ？
focus in on those 27 errors so think
关注那27个错误，所以想一想
these are errors these are not bad
这些都是错误，这些都不错
sectors okay remember the difference
部门还好记住差异
there so it's not saying that these are
所以不是 说 这些 都是
bad parts of the drive it's saying I
驱动器的坏部分，它说 我
encountered an error at that point while
那时遇到了错误
I was copying so by going back over it
我正在通过回过头来 复制
again DD rescue may say oh okay now that
再次DD救援可能会说哦现在好了
we've taken a bit more time I've been
我们花了很多时间去过
able to get a couple more of those
能够得到 更多这些
blocks oh so all of a sudden you're
阻止哦 所以 突然间你
gonna see that the error count goes down
会看到错误计数下降
because again it's not referring to bad
因为 它不是指坏的
sectors it's referring to a problem
它指的是一个问题
during the rescue process right which is
这是 抢救过程中的权利
going to decrease as it is able to go
随着它能够 去 减少
back over those so let's look back at
回到了那些让我们回头看看
Chris's screenshot here and Chris one of
克里斯的截图在这里和克里斯之一
the key things that we notice here is
我们在这里注意到的关键事项是
the error size okay see that one just
错误大小可以看到那个只是
above your errors count the error size
在您的错误之上计算错误大小
is very small this is a 250 gig disk you
非常小，这 是 一个250 gig磁盘你
can see that just to the left of left of
可以看到 就在左边的左边
that or at least that's how much it had
那或者至少 它有多少
rescued and we see that it's finished so
获救，我们看到它的完成 使
we can assume that this is probably a
我们可以假设这 可能是一个
250 gig disk because it's not going to
250 gig 磁盘，因为它不会
be much much different than that because
与此有很大不同，因为
it's finished so look at the error size
它已经完成， 所以请 查看错误大小
124 kilobytes of 250
240千字节的 124千字节
bytes we're talking what is that zero
字节 我们正在谈论什么是 零
point zero zero zero three percent
零点零零三点
something like that a very very small
类似的东西非常 非常小
amount of data so chances you know it is
数据量，所以 你很有 可能 知道它
data loss go back let it loop over it
数据丢失回去让它循环
try to get that data and put it in your
尝试获取数据并将其放入您的数据中
image file so that you've got all of the
图像文件， 这样你就可以得到所有的
data and you don't lose any is the drive
数据， 你不丢失任何 是驱动器
failing is it has it failed is it is it
失败的是它失败了是不是它
problematic is it something that needs
有问题的是 它 需要的 东西
to be replaced or that you need to be
被替换或你需要
concerned with certainly the fact that
当然关心这个 事实
there are errors on the drive means that
驱动器上有错误意味着
it is there is something up okay if it's
如果有的话，还有什么好的
is a catastrophic that's what we want to
是灾难性的，这是我们想要的
determine so I'm gonna jump over to my
确定所以我 要 跳 过去 我
Linux system here for you and we're
Linux系统在这里为您和我们而存在
gonna get into our terminal so let's do
要进入我们的终端让我们这样做
that make sure I bring up the rights
这确保我 提出了权利
great here we go
我们 走的 很棒
okay so Chris what we're gonna do and
好吧，所以克里斯，我们要做什么和
for all of you watching what we're gonna
因为你们所有人都在看我们要做什么
learn here is how to determine if your
在这里学习是如何确定 你的
hard drive is in fact failing if there
硬盘驱动器 实际上是失败的，如果有
is something that sector-by-sector copy
是逐个部门复制的东西
can't see because those are two
看不清楚 因为那是 两个
different readings what we want to look
不同的读数我们想看什么
at is the smart status of our hard drive
at是我们硬盘的智能状态
you've probably heard the term what it
你可能已经听过这个词了
means is there's there's data that's
意味着是否存在数据
stored on your hard drive about your
存储在您的硬盘上 关于您的
hard drives status so every time there's
每次都有硬盘驱动器状态
a problem with your drive it's going to
与 您的驱动器这将有问题
report it and the only way to see that
报告它和看到它的唯一方法
is to use a tool that looks at your
是 使用一个 看你 的工具
smart data so let's get in here and
智能数据，以便让我们在这里
let's try it let's I'm gonna just see if
让我们来试试吧，让我们我 要 进去 看看
I have it in start so smart did I say in
我开始时就这么聪明 了
starred because I'm typing smart smart
因为我打字聪明聪明而出演
and I said in I don't know what I said
我说我不知道​​我说了什么
we're gonna see if I have it installed
我们会看看我是否安装了它
by typing smart CTL and it says
通过键入智能CTL，它说
obviously I I do have it installed
显然 我 我有它 安装
because it's not giving me an error but
因为它没有给我 一个错误 但是
the program is missing now if it did
如果有的话，该程序现在不见了
give me an error that there that the
给我一个错误， 那就是那个
program was missing the the package that
程序缺少的包
you want to install is so you would go
你 要安装就是这样你会去的
sudo apt-get update enter your password
sudo apt-get update 输入您的密码
and then once she's done sudo apt-get
然后，一旦她完成了sudo apt-get
install smart Mon tools that's what
安装智能Mon工具就是这样
you're gonna need Chris and everyone
你需要克里斯和所有人
else okay and it says smart Mon tools is
别的没关系，它说聪明的Mon工具是
already the newest version that's what
已经是最新版本了
my system tells me I've already got it
我的系统告诉我，我已经知道了
in there see that nice okay so I'm good
在那里看到那个很好，所以我很好
so smart CTL dash 8 just gonna give you
如此聪明的CTL 冲刺8 就会给你
a little bit of information about how
一些 关于如何的信息
you use it and if you're in your
你使用它 ，如果你在你的
terminal like this you can scroll up
像这样的终端你可以向上滚动
cool so what we need to do is we want to
很酷我们需要做的就是我们想要的
test or see the test results that are
测试或查看测试结果
currently on that drive smart CTL - -
目前在那个驱动智能CTL  -   -
all and then the drive the drive dev
所有然后驱动驱动器开发
assignment we already know that because
任务我们已经知道因为
on episode 490 we used F disk - L to
上一集490我们使用F盘 - L到
determine that let's do it again really
确定让我们真的再做一次
really quickly just so that we know F
真的很快 就让我们知道F.
disk no I'm gonna need sudo pardon me
磁盘没有我需要sudo原谅我
sudo fdisk - L and we see that I only
sudo fdisk  -  L，我们 只 看到了
have s da in my system so SDA one means
在我的系统中有SD， 所以SDA意味着
partition the first partition - is the
分区第一个分区- 是
second and the third and the fifth and
第二，第三和第五和
the sixth are actually the fourth and
第六个实际上是第四个和
the fifth
第五
we know ya figure that the drive itself
我们知道你认为 驱动器本身
is called slash dev slash SDA so I'm
被称为slash dev slash SDA所以我是
going to type smart CTL - - all slash
打算输入智能CTL  -   - 所有斜线
dev slash SDA and then hit enter what
开发斜杠SDA然后点击进入什么
does it tell us permission denied okay
它告诉我们许可否认没问题
why because I forgot sudo sudo you have
为什么因为 我忘了 你有 sudo sudo
to be super user there we go okay so
要成为超级用户，我们就可以了
gave me a big report here and if I
在这里给了我一个很好的报告，如果我
scroll up you're gonna see a couple of
向上滚动你会看到 几个
things first of all okay well no it says
事情首先好吧没有它说
pre fail pre fail pre-fill pre-fill pre
预先失败预先填充预填充预先
fail oh no my drive is crashing no don't
失败哦没有我的驱动器崩溃没有不
freak out don't worry you're okay you're
吓坏你不要 担心 你没问题
okay why why because the raw value is
好吧为什么，因为原始值是
zero zero that means it never happened
零归零意味着它从未发生过
okay what is this yeah this is the type
好吧 ，这是什么呀，这是类型
the type of this particular error raw
这个特殊错误的类型原始
read error rate
读错误率
is prevail so okay so you're just
是占上风 所以好了， 你只是
looking in the wrong spot hmm so if my
看着错误的地方嗯 所以，如果我的
raw value for this particular line in
此特定行的原始值
the table happens to be greater than
表恰好是大于
zero then we know that we have a pre
零， 那么我们知道我们有一个pre
fail error on our drive that means it's
我们的驱动器上的失败错误意味着它
about to crash you're about to lose all
即将崩溃你将失去一切
your data it might be a year from now it
你的数据可能 是从 现在开始 的一年
might be a day from now but you need to
可能是从 现在开始 的一天， 但你需要
replace this drive if you see any
如果你看到任何，请更换此驱动器
reasonable number of pre fail errors
合理数量的预失败错误
happening on that road anything greater
发生在那条路上的事情更大
than zero
比零
realistically guy I mean if you've got a
现实主义者我的意思是，如果你 有一个
pre fail error you know that your drive
预失败错误你知道 你的驱动器
is failing and we need to replace it you
失败了， 我们需要替换你
know you need to get rockin on on that
知道你需要 得到的是对摇滚
if there's one or two or 50 or 50 yeah I
如果有一个或两个或50或50 是的我
mean if that's the case then you know
如果是这样的话就意味着你知道了
you'd probably don't need to freak out
你可能不需要 吓坏了
right now don't like it's failing okay
现在不喜欢它失败了
don't get me wrong don't get me wrong I
别误会我 不要 误会 我的意思
want you to replace it but where you
希望 你替换它但你在哪里
really like I mean you could still be
真的像我的意思 你仍然 可以
running your computer and have 50,000
运行你的 电脑，有 50,000
pre fail errors right and you'll be why
预先失败的错误，你会成为 原因
is my computer so darn slow right
是我的电脑，以便 正确 织补慢
because you're hard driving you've seen
因为 你已经看到了很难驾驶
this where your hard drive gets really
这是你的硬盘真正的地方
really like choked up and all of a
真的很喜欢哽咽起来，所有 的
sudden yeah and then your computer just
突然是的，然后你的电脑
seems to freeze up yeah and then all of
似乎冻结了啊，然后所有 的
a sudden it starts working again and
突然它开始再次合作 ，
something you think okay I must have
一些你觉得好吧 ，我必须有
just been doing something no that's your
只是做了 一些不是你的事
hard drive pre failing that's the
硬盘驱动器预先失败了
internal storage getting ready to crash
内部存储准备崩溃
and that's called a pre fail problems so
而 这就是所谓的预失效 问题，所以
it's having trouble reading sectors of
它在 阅读部门时遇到了麻烦
the drive and that's that's critical
驱动器，这是至关重要的
really scary yeah so as that starts
真的很可怕， 所以一开始
happening now remember that Chris has
现在发生的事情记得 克里斯有
followed the instructions on episode 490
按照第490集的说明进行操作
made an image of his friend's hard drive
形成了他朋友的硬盘
so now on Chris's laptop there is a full
所以现在克里斯的笔记本电脑上有一个完整的
image a copy of this hard drive so you
想象一下这个硬盘的副本吧
can go out and buy a new hard drive and
可以 出去买一个新的 硬盘和
then image that back and she's lost no
然后回来的形象，她没有失去
data that's cool well 120 some odd
很酷的数据120有些奇怪
kilobytes of data nothing significant
千字节的数据没什么大不了的
but maybe if you loop over a couple more
但也许，如果你遍历一对夫妇 更多
times it'll it'll get rid of it so look
时间它会摆脱它 所以看起来
at this list okay and you see how some
在这个列表好吧，你看到了一些
of them say old age look at this oh my
他们说晚年看这个 哦我的
goodness uh 649
善良呃649
oh it's only old age it's not prevail
哦，这是唯一的年龄，它并不 盛行
what it's saying is that yeah this is
这是什么意思，是的，是的
normal for a drive that's been in
正常的驱动器 已进入
operation for some time okay so this is
操作一段时间没关系， 所以这是
not something that you necessarily have
不是你必须拥有的东西
to be concerned with that particular
关心那个 特别的
thing is telling me that it has been
事情告诉我 它已经 存在
that my hard drive has been powered on
我的硬盘已经开机了
for a total of six hundred forty nine
一共六百四 十九
hours okay so mine is obviously a fairly
小时没关系所以我的显然是公平的
new drive right so the fact that it says
新的驱动器正确 的事实，它 说
old age is not saying I have an old aged
晚年是不是说我有一个老年
hard drive so when you say when you see
硬盘驱动器， 所以当你说的时候
pre fail it's not saying your drive is
预先 失败并不是说你的驱动器是
pre failing no it's saying this
预先失败没有它说这个
particular line in this table is about
该表中的特定行是 关于
old age it's reporting on old age mm-hmm
老年人报告老年人 mm-hmm
well it's this is the it's reporting on
好吧，这是它的报道
the number of hours that's been online
这一直是 网上的小时数
so when you see 649 I offer of old age
所以，当你看到649我提供的晚年
right now if I saw something there that
现在如果我看到的东西有没有
said 10 million then yeah my drive is
说1000 万然后是我的驱动器
pretty old yes so you see how so the pre
很老，是的， 所以你看到预备如何
fail stuff we're not really we you know
失败的东西我们 真的不是你知道的
that's more critical right and those are
那是更重要的权利， 那些是
real those are real oh yeah
真的是真的哦是的
like if I turn off my laptop it stops
就像我关掉笔记本电脑一样停下来
counting okay yeah that's real time
算好， 是的，这是实时的
super accurate that's real time okay
超级准确 ，这是实时的好
that's good I do see you know some
这很好， 我确实看到你知道一些
things here that I'm not sure what they
这里的事情，我 不确定他们 是 什么
are like here's a pre fail where I have
我喜欢这里是一个失败的地方
707 but it says unknown attribute so I'd
707但它表示未知的属性，所以我
have to look that up which I will allow
必须看看我会允许的
you to Google code number ID 170 what is
你到 谷歌的代号 是什么？
it comment below okay Chris and everyone
它评论下面好的克里斯和大家
else I hope that gives you a little bit
否则 我希望能给你一点点
more insight so Chris as you look at
更有见地，所以克里斯看你
that report on your friend's hard drive
报告你朋友的硬盘
that's now when you can say okay well
现在你可以说好了
I'd yeah okay DeeDee Rescue had some
我没关系DeeDee Rescue有一些
trouble copy and some some bits of data
麻烦复制和一些数据
running over it again may get that data
再次运行它可能会获得该数据
off of there so that I've got a full
离开那里， 这样我就满了
image what I really need to see now that
想象我现在真正需要看到的东西
I know that there are some errors with
我知道 有 一些错误
the drive is is the drive in a pre fail
驱动器是预先失败的驱动器
state I can tell that by looking at
我可以通过 观察 来判断
those pre fail lines and seeing if the
那些预先失败的线，看看是否
raw value is a high number yeah that's
原始值很高， 是的
going to tell us that that drive is on
要告诉我们 那个驱动器已 开启
its way out if
它的出路 ，如果
not already dead all right
不是已经死了 没事
[Music]
[音乐]